TAREK NII KPAKPO QUAO

(+233) 276733434 tarek.quao@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/tarekguao

I am a software Engineer with over 1 year's experience designing and developing, as well as testing and debugging websites. Aspiring to excel as a Software Engineer by combining development background with technical skills to provide quality web-based solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BEWSYS, Accra, Ghana

Associate Software Engineer

August 2020 - August 2021

- Develop the frontend and backend of websites using HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and Laravel.
- Develop and maintain client websites with Content Management Systems like WordPress.
- Optimize existing websites to improve web functionality and responsiveness.
- Integrate SMS feature into a website for more inclusive user account creation and verification.
- Design user interfaces with Figma.

Apex Marketing, Accra, Ghana

Web Developer

November 2021 - Present

- Design and Build websites using Wordpress.
- Manage and client Ecommerce websites built with WooCommerce.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

Automated Umbrella Dispenser, **Fullstack Developer**

April - May 2019

- Developed the website frontend for managing an umbrella dispenser, using HTML, CSS.
 - Developed the backend in PHP to interact with the database for the system for record-keeping and user verification.
- Used MySQL as the database for its scalability and flexibility.

Galamsey Information System

March - April 2019

Backend Developer

- Developed an information system (in Java) in a team of 4 which is used to record data GPS coordinates from a drone which identifies 'Galamsey' (illegal mining) sites.
- Built system module for interacting with database (MySQL) to record, read, update, and delete information.

Smart Solar Irrigation System

June - July 2017

Software Developer, 3D Designer

- Designed and built a smart miniature solar-powered irrigation system in a team of 4.
- Connected the various sensor circuits to the Arduino microcontroller.
- Programmed the Arduino board (in C) to control the sensors and system logic.

Speeding Ticket Issuing System (Capstone)

September 2019 - May 2020

- **Full Stack Developer**
- Conducted research on past road accidents in Ghana before 2019.
- Developed the backend of the system using Python Flask framework.
- Designed and developed the frontend for managing records in the system with HTML, CSS.
- Implemented an automatic email feature for fined vehicle owners.
- Included dynamic pdf generation for various vehicle owners with varying amounts fined for over speeding.
- Put down a report summing up findings and system requirements

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

TECHERA

Tech Module Tutor

November 2016 - September 2017

- Taught high school students basic computer knowledge, including how to use the computer.
- Taught high school students how to use MS Word and Excel.
- Coordinated the Organization's robotics competition amongst primary school students, together with other tutors.

EDUCATION

ASHESI UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

BSc. Computer Engineering

Accra, Greater Accra Date of Graduation: June 2020

GPA: 3.39 / 4.00

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS/Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP (Laravel), MySQL, MVC.
- WordPress
- Figma
- Java, Python
- Jira, version control